本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 红鼻子的UFO Nothing blfoxcon 猫 水涟漪 小白
校对： 小安   后期： Pilar
彼岸是天堂
第二季 第二集
克莱曼斯! 很高兴再次见到你!
Clemence! What a delight it is to see you again!
亲爱的莫里 巴黎非常想念你
My darling Moray! Paris misses you so much.
没有你帅气的脸庞 乐篷马歇百货就是个惨淡之处
Le Bon Marche is a dismal place without your handsome face.
没人像你一样恭维我 小姐
No-one flatters me as you do, Mademoiselle.
亲爱的 我想要诱惑你
My darling, I intend to tempt you.
你会让我勾引你的 对吗?
You will let me seduce you, won't you?
我有拒绝过你吗 克莱曼斯?
Did I ever deny you, Clemence?
她在跟他说什么?
What did she say to him?
- 不知道 - 不管是啥我都希望她是在对我说
- Don't know. - Whatever it was, I wish she was saying it to me!
失陪一下
Excuse me.
迄今 谁能承受这样的奢侈无度?
Until now, who could afford such extravagance?
唯有富人
Only the wealthy.
我总觉得乐趣都浪费在富人身上了 你不觉得吗?
I always feel that fun is wasted on the rich, don't you?
我希望有足够的欢乐充盈在我们的生活里
There's enough pleasures in life to go around, I hope.
我也希望
I hope so too.
我们找到了一种工艺手法使每个人都买得起
We have found a way to make my beautiful creations
我美丽的作品
so that anyone can afford them.
你希望我们在天堂百货出售它们?
And you want us to offer them in The Paradise?
你让我失望了 亲爱的!
Oh, you disappoint me, darling!
那个在巴黎施展魔法的莫里到哪去了?
Where is the Moray who cast his spell over Paris?
不是出售它们 不 是推销它们
Not offer them, no. Sell them.
大量卖出它们
Sell lots of them.
克莱曼斯 如果你把烟花做得很便宜...
Clemence, if you make the fireworks cheaply...
对不起 我们别再多费口舌了
Oh, please, let us not waste our lives talking.
今晚 我会展示给你 亲爱的 我们要点亮天空
I will show you. Tonight. Darling, we will light up the skies.
他在他的信里提到过她吗?
So, did he write about her in his letters, then?
没 没 他没有
No. No, he didn't.
我以为他会 如果我认识像她这样的人 我会
Well, you'd think he would. If I met someone like her, I would.
那么 谁会接手奥德丽小姐的工作呢?
So, whose going to get Miss Audrey's job, then?
我还没走呢 梅尔托
I am not departed quite yet, Myrtle.
我只是说说 奥德丽小姐 既然你要结婚
I'm only saying, Miss Audrey. Since you're to marry,
他们会希望有人接手你的职位
they'll be wanting someone for your position.
我不得不说 这一切都太突然了
I have to say, it is all rather sudden.
你可以不说 梅尔托 你不说没人当你是哑巴
You don't "have to say," Myrtle, you choose to say.
我主张二十三年恋爱期
And I would contend that 23 years of courtship
一定要有节有礼
has a certain decorum to it.
我不知道 二十三分钟的求爱我都觉得慢
I wouldn't know! Twenty-three minutes' wooing is slow for me!
我们都为您高兴 奥德丽小姐
We're very pleased for you, Miss Audrey.
你有婚礼要计划 还有蜜月
You'll have to plan the wedding. And the honeymoon.
这些都要花时间 你不会马上结婚的
That all takes time. You're not getting married right away, like.
所以你暂时还不会离开
So, you're not leaving us just yet.
是啊 我们拭目以待
Yes. Well. We shall see.
如果我要结婚 我才不会有那种表情
If I was getting married, I wouldn't be wearing a face like that.
确实让你起了好奇心了 不是吗?
Well, it does make you wonder, doesn't it?
谁将是女装部的主管?
Who will be Head of Ladieswear?
夫人 请问... 你是在想.....
Ma'am, may I ask... were you thinking.....?
你会很快结婚吗?
Will you be marrying soon?
我考虑了多少年啊?
How many years have I considered?
如果我结婚 我会失去我的工作
If I marry, I will lose my position.
如果我工作下去
If I hold on to my employment,
我永远也不会知道婚姻的乐趣
I will never know the joys of marriage.
我深思熟虑 反复思考 又被优柔寡断困住
I deliberate and ruminate and I'm frozen with indecision.
我唯一的办法就是冒险
So...the only way is for me to leap.
冒险?
Leap?
如果我犹豫不决 我将独身而死 我有一些存款
If I dither, I will die a spinster. I have some savings.
我兄弟在海边留给我一间小屋
A cottage that my brother left to me by the sea.
我已经告诉莫里先生我要走了
I have told Mr Moray that I am leaving.
结婚
Marrying.
离开
Leaving.
你好 小姐们
Bonjour, Mademoiselle.
我非常喜欢长拖尾
Oh, I do so love the long trains.
还有剪裁 它为什么能如此契合女人的身材!
And the cut, what it does for a woman's body!
还有比这更有女人味的吗?
Is there anything more feminine?
告诉我你怎么看的 克莱拉
Tell me what you think, Clara.
百褶荷叶边的确显得轻柔 夫人
The pleated ruffles do give a soft influence, Ma'am.
哦 拜托 我知道你们英国人比较喜欢用尊称
Oh. Please. I know how you English do so prefer your deference,
但你一定要叫我克莱曼斯
but you must call me Clemence.
蝴蝶结 扣子 还有穗带
Bows, buttons, and braids.
我们为什么那么喜欢它们?
Why do we love them so much?
是因为它们使人眼前一亮吗?
Is it because they draw the eye?
我觉得我们的每个决定都是可控制的 不
I think that every decision we make is guided, no,
由激情决定
determined by passion.
亦或是情欲 你们怎么看 姑娘们?
Sexual passion. What do you think, girls?
或许 夫人 我建议
Perhaps, Madam, I might suggest,
试试用彩带丝绒帽作陪衬怎么样?
to accompany the silk velvet hat with the ribbon streamers?
你当然是对的 因为你是一个了解自己行业的女人
Of course you are right, because you are a woman who knows her calling.
谢谢 女士 夫人 小姐
Thank you, Madam. Ma'am. Mademoiselle.
克莱曼斯
Clemence.
这是我第一次来天堂百货
It is only my first visit to The Paradise
但 奥德丽小姐 我无法想象没有你在这里的场景
but, Miss Audrey, I cannot imagine this place without you.
看到了吗 亚瑟? 加点焰火会发生什么?
See that, Arthur? Add a bit of a flame and what happens?
物体开始旋转 四溅火花
Stuff starts spinning, sparks shooting
还会满天飞
and flying all over the place.
你会想到什么?
What does that remind you of?
一场暴风雨?
A thunderstorm?
女人 亚瑟 女人
Women, Arthur. Women.
是啊 但这美丽又刺激
Yeah, but it's pretty and exciting.
亚瑟 我的小伙儿 你刚描述了男人永恒的困境
Arthur, me lad, you have just described man's eternal dilemma.
她非常美丽 不是吗 德妮丝?
She's so beautiful, in't she, Denise?
我无法想象做那样的女人是什么感觉
I can't imagine what it must be like to be such a woman.
你能想象吗 我打赌男人都会拜倒在她的石榴裙下
Can you? I bet men fall for her all the time.
如果我是男人 我也会爱上她 你会吗 德妮丝?
If I was a man, I'd fall for her. Would you, Denise?
我想我会抗拒
I think I could resist.
我从来没觉得法国人是那么的...法国风味儿
I never realised that French people were so... French.
我的意思是 所有那些抚摸啦 亲吻啦
I mean, all that touching'n kissing'n
调情啦
flirting.
克莱曼斯 这是汤姆・威斯顿先生
Clemence, this is Mr Tom Weston.
他是天堂百货的老板
He's the owner of The Paradise.
罗马尼斯小姐 我希望你能感觉到宾至如归
Mademoiselle Romanis. I hope you've been made welcome.
莫里总是非常慷慨
Moray is always most generous.
我不希望你觉得我们英国人像传说一样
I would not wish you to think that we English
冷淡而且不好客
are as cold and inhospitable as our reputation.
你逗留的这段时间 或许我们可以一起吃顿饭?
Perhaps you might have dinner with me while you're here?
我很荣幸 威斯顿先生
I would be delighted, Monsieur Weston.
我不介乎你相信我们法国人
I would not care for you to believe we French
像耳闻那样的无礼
are as rude as our reputation.
- 失陪一下 - 你要在英国待多久?
- Excuse me. - So, how long will you be staying?
我们的婚礼需要来点像烟花
Wouldn't it be something to have fireworks like that
这样的东西吗 奥德丽?
at our wedding, Audrey?
我们这年龄段? 这会显得轻率又没品位
At our age? It would be brash and tasteless.
我们必须低调 艾德蒙!
We must reach for understatement, Edmund!
我们这个年龄段 我的意思是我们需要庆祝
At our age, I say we should celebrate.
你似乎对她友好过头了
You just seem awfully friendly with her, that's all.
我是对克莱曼斯非常友好
I am awfully friendly with Clemence.
你在巴黎时经常和她见面吗?
Did you see her when you were in Paris?
三天两头见!
All the time!
我是采购员 她是乐篷马歇百货最好的供货方
I was a buyer and she was the best supplier we had at Le Bon Marche.
你和她一起吃过饭吗?
Did you dine with her?
有啊! 她是个极好的同伴
Yes! She's wonderful company.
德妮丝 抱歉 但克莱曼斯不是我喜欢的类型
Denise. I'm sorry, but Clemence is not my type,
我保证不管你看到了什么 我也不是她喜欢的类型
and I can assure you, despite what you see, I'm not her type either.
你觉得 你会想念这里吗?
Will you miss the street, do you think?
我们可能永远不会离开!
We might never leave!
我放了出售牌 看客比想买的人多
I put that sign up. Not had so much as a peep through the window.
在我兄弟去世之后 他的小屋就一直空着了
My brother's cottage is standing empty. It has been since he died.
我们这个周末去那整理一下 做好准备
We'll head up there at weekends, do some work, make it ready.
我一直在琢磨...
I have been wondering...
...我们为什么要等呢?
..why must we wait?
告诉我关于威斯顿的事 他结婚了吗?
Tell me about Mr Weston. He is married?
结了 他和凯瑟琳・格伦德宁结婚了
Oh, yes. He is married to Katherine Glendenning.
我听说过她
Oh, I have heard about her.
她是莫里去巴黎的原因
She is the reason Moray was in Paris.
她可不是个好惹的女人
She's not a woman to be crossed.
价格挺合理的
The price is good.
这周末烟火就能到我们店了
We can have the firecrackers in our store by the end of the week.
我们不能让她相信我们已经做出决定了
We must not let her believe that we've made a decision yet.
先生 我已经向克莱曼斯提了...
Sir, I have already indicated to Clemence...
那你太草率了
Then you were too hasty.
威斯顿先生 这个展示已经证明了她的产品有多好
Mr Weston, the display has proven how good her product is.
晚告诉她有什么好处?
What benefit is there in delay?
如果让她感觉到我们太积极
If she feels we're too keen,
这交易的主动权就到她手里了
then the deal will be made on her terms.
就让她噱我们好了
Let her woo us.
他们在讨论你
They're talking about you.
他们是男人 他们在谈论公事
They are men. They are talking about business.
威斯顿先生正在告诉他们直到他带我去吃晚餐前
Mr Weston is telling them that they must not offer me the contract
不要跟我签合约
until he has taken me out to dinner.
他死了吗?
Is he dead?
乔纳斯! 把他带进去
Jonas! Get him inside.
德妮丝 盛点热水来
Denise, fetch some hot water.
我们至少能把这可怜的家伙打理干净
Least we can do is clean the poor feller up.
所有不相干的人全给我出去
I want anybody who is not needed out of this room now.
包括老板 所有老板
Bosses included. Bosses most of all.
他发烧了
That's a fever if ever I saw one.
克莱拉 把他身上的脏衣服脱了
Clara, let's have these filthy clothes off him.
山姆 把你的睡衣拿来
Sam, fetch one of your nightgowns.
我? 为什么一定要我的睡衣?
Me? Why does it have to be mine?
因为你有个好心肠 年轻的女士会因此爱你的
Because you're a kindly soul and the young women'll love you for it.
我现在就去拿
I'll fetch it right away.
他为什么要回来?
Why has he come back?
他会不会知道我回到天堂百货了?
D'you suppose he knows I have returned to The Paradise?
困扰我的是 为什么警察没有跟着他?
What has troubled me is - why did the constable not come after him?
街上到处都是伯勒斯的死讯
The street was full of whispers about Burroughs' death
还有乔纳斯脱罪出狱的消息
and Jonas walked away a free man.
我得感谢他出来了
I must be thankful that he did.
把乔纳斯留在这对我们就意味着一件事--危险
Then having Jonas here can only mean one thing for us - danger.
他病了! 我们得收留他
He's sick! We must give him shelter.
- 为什么? - 我们欠他的
- Why must we? - We owe Jonas that much.
先等他好起来吧 然后再看看他想要什么
Just let him get well, then we'll see what he wants,
然后就赶他走
then we'll get rid of him.
在...在小巷里...里...见
Me... meet me in.... in the alleyway...
八...八...八点
eight... eight... eight... eight o'clock.
告诉...告诉...告诉
Tell... tell.... tell...
- 他在说什么? - 他发着烧呢
What's he saying? - He is fevered.
他可能在说世界末日要到了
He could be saying the end of the world is nigh.
乔纳斯・弗兰克斯不发烧也会说这些东西
Jonas Franks doesn't need a fever to say the likes of that.
- 巴拉斯...巴拉斯 - 嘘...嘘
- Barrass... Baarrass.... - Shhh, shhh.
别说话
Don't talk.
睡觉吧 你现在安全了
Sleep. You're going to be safe now.
我已经忘了我是来天堂百货做生意的
I might forget I have come to The Paradise to do business
反而天天和闺蜜们在这儿
and spend all of my time here with girls
你的房间满是财宝
and your room full of treasures.
你的愉快也是我们的愉快 克莱曼斯女士
We are pleased that you are pleased, Mademoiselle Clemence.
原谅我 但我昨天偷听到段对话
Forgive me, but I overheard the conversation yesterday.
你要离开了?
You are leaving?
嫁人? 约翰是疯了吧
To marry? Is John insane...
错失了那么一个宝物?
..to lose such a diamond?
当一个女人结婚时 她一定要放弃公事
When a woman marries, she must forfeit her office.
在面纱撩起之前 她已经走出办公门了
She's out of the door before the veil's pulled from her face.
但是也有结婚的男人依旧在这儿工作的
But there are men who work here who are married?
达德利先生 男装部的克莱夫
Mr Dudley. Clive in Menswear.
男装部的艾伦 杂货商店的大卫
Alan in Menswear. David in Haberdashery...
是的 谢谢你 克莱拉 一般的看门人都是已婚的
Yes, thank you, Clara. Half the porters are married.
如果女人是想要生孩子的 可能我会理解
Perhaps I might understand if woman intends to have children,
但你不是这样的 不是吗 奥德丽?
but that is not so with you, is it, Audrey?
我解释过了 女士 就是这样的
As I have explained, Mademoiselle, it is the way.
是啊 就是这样
Oh, yes! It is the way.
就是这样让男人决定一切
It is the way the men have decided upon.
- 德妮丝 - 克莱曼斯女士
- Denise... Mademoiselle Clemence.
莫里的女人
Moray's girl.
我现在知道为什么在巴黎时
I see now why he spoke of nothing but Denise, Denise, Denise
他嘴上老是挂着德妮丝 德妮丝 德妮丝了
all of the time in Paris.
我相信这不是真的 女士
I'm sure that's not true, Mademoiselle.
对女人只有一件事比
There is only one thing more heartbreaking for a woman
和一个满怀欲望的男人吃饭更心碎
than a dinner with a man perspiring with lust,
那就是和一个渴望得到爱的男人共进晚餐
and that is dinner with a man pining for his love.
但现在我看到你了 我能原谅他
But now that I see you, I can forgive him.
德妮丝 关于奥德丽小姐的困境 你怎么看?
What do you think of Miss Audrey's predicament, Denise?
我...
I...
我很高兴她想要结婚
..I'm pleased that she wishes to marry,
和她爱的人在一起
and to be with the man that she loves.
但这不是我问的问题
But that is not what I asked you.
一个女人的职位被剥夺
What do you think of a woman robbed of her position,
一个有经验 各方面品质优秀的女人
a woman with experience, a woman brimming with best qualities,
因为我们身在男人的世界而被否决 你怎么看?
cast out because we live in a man's world?
我认为这是错的
I think it's wrong.
当然了
Course you do.
你们女孩子晚上都在干嘛?
What do you girls do with yourself in the evenings?
- 我会去对面街的酒屋 - 那今晚我们一起去
- I go to the inn across the street. - Ahhh, we will all go there tonight.
女士 那地方是昏暗的小地方
Mademoiselle, it's a murky little den of a place.
我不确定你会不会喜欢
I'm not sure you'd find it to your tastes.
我能借点纸吗? 我得写封信给威斯顿先生
Might I borrow some paper? I must write a note to Mr Weston
告诉他我今晚不能和他吃晚饭了
to tell him I cannot join him for dinner after all.
今晚我很忙
I'm busy tonight.
奥德丽小姐 你一起来吗?
Miss Audrey, you will join us?
小酒馆? 我从来没有...
The inn? I-I have never...
我...我不赞同...
I... I would not countenance...
酒馆
the inn.
但你不好奇吗? 我很好奇诶 我已经邀请你了
But aren't you curious? I am. I have invited you.
你不会拒绝你法国来的客人吧 是吗?
You wouldn't offend your French guest by refusing, would you?
你为什么回来 乔纳斯?
Why have you come back, Jonas?
我不是自己想过来的 先生
I did not come here at my own bidding, sir.
我是被带来的
I was brought here.
你不受欢迎 没人想你来
You're not welcome. You're not wanted.
我很多东西都看不透了 先生 但这个我看出来了
I don't see much clearly at the moment, sir, but I see that.
关于伯勒斯的死
The business with Burroughs' death -
为什么警察没有来抓你?
why did the constable not come after you?
没什么神秘的 达德利先生
There is no mystery, Mr Dudley, sir.
我贿赂他了
I paid the man.
和这一带很多人一样
Like many people hereabouts,
他对布拉德利・伯勒斯也没什么好感
he had no regard for Bradley Burroughs.
你杀人了
You murdered a man.
如果你想象这种安排就能让你呆在这了
If you imagine that such an arrangement allows you to stay here,
那你就大错特错了
then you are mistaken.
麦片粥 这比把肉放在人上好多了
Porridge. It's better than meat for putting meat on a man.
你一直爱你的麦片粥 乔纳斯先生
You always loved your porridge, Mr Jonas.
你怎么会落到这步田地?
How did you come to be in such a state?
我不知道
I don't know.
你怎么会在那马车上的?
How did you come to be on that wagon?
我不知道
I don't know.
你不知道的有点多啊
You don't know a lot, do you?
高烧榨干了你的活力
The fever has drained the life out of you.
等到你能走路了 你就可以走了
When you're well enough to walk, you'll be on your way.
我想你可以安排个烟火的展示
..so I thought you could put on a display of the fireworks,
邀请各种各样的人 然后在街上摆一个摊头
invite all kinds of people and set up a stall on the street
卖烟火
to sell the firecrackers.
现在你喜欢克莱曼斯了?
So you like Clemence now?
我应该无视这个
I shall ignore that.
这是个很棒的点子 我很高兴我想到了它
It's a marvellous idea. I'm glad I thought of it.
我眼里容不下别的女人 德妮丝 她们都不存在
I have no eyes for other women, Denise. They do not exist.
我已经找到我要娶的女人了
I have found the woman I will marry.
我好高兴 亲爱的
I am so glad, my darling,
你已经着手天堂百货的事务了
you have readily taken to the business of The Paradise.
但我得承认 我没想到你会天天去那里
But I must confess, I didn't imagine you would go in there every day.
莫里找了个法国女人供烟花给他
Moray has a French woman supplying him with fireworks.
我得确保他不会被骗做亏本买卖
I want to make sure he isn't beguiled into a bad deal.
烟花! 爸爸 我能不能去看看?
Firecrackers! Can I see them, Daddy?
她是个法国人?
So she's French?
对啊
Yes.
今天我会和她共进晚餐
I'm having dinner with her tonight.
我很高兴你能发现天堂百货的迷人之处 亲爱的
Well, I am glad you find The Paradise so engaging...darling.
女装部的主管要离职了
The head of Ladieswear is leaving.
奥德丽小姐?
Miss Audrey?
对 她要结婚了
Yeah. She is to marry.
所以说有女店员要晋升了?
So one of the girls will be promoted?
有什么关系么?
Does it matter?
我意识到 只要我还是为男人工作
I realised that so long as I worked for a man
我就永远都只是一个...
I would never be more than a...
所有物? 你们的说法是什么?
saisine. What do you say?
奴隶?
A chattel?
奴隶
A chattel.
我审视这些男人然后问我自己
I looked at the men and I asked myself,
我能否做到他们做的这些?
can I do what they do?
答案是肯定的
And the answer was yes.
答案是我可以比他们做得更好
The answer was I can do it better than they do.
所以你就开始自己做生意了?
So you started your own business?
我了解了人们想要买什么东西
I have an idea of something people might like to buy,
我找到了能帮我达成目标的人
I find someone who can make it for me,
我给乐蓬马歇百货或者其他商店供货
I supply to Le Bon Marche or any other store.
- 我活得很滋润 - 我只庆幸我有份工作
- I live a good life. - I'm just happy to have a job.
这种事情在法国很常见 小姐
That is all very well in France, Mademoiselle.
在英国 我们更倾向于遵守我们的传统
In England, we prefer to cling on to our civilisation.
传统能让你感到满足吗?
Does this civilisation make you feel contented?
天啊! 这是后宫还是妇女会什么的吗?
Good Lord! Is it a harem or a hen party?
你也可以参加啊 山姆 你基本就是个女人嘛
You can join us, Sam. You're as good as one of the girls.
嘿! 我不是女人 请您不要乱说
Hey! I am not one of the girls, if you don't mind.
有那么一两个姑娘可以证明
There's one or two lass can prove it.
我去吧台喝一杯
I'll have a drink at the bar.
来 大家把酒杯举起来 所有人 稍等
Please, lift up your glass, all of you. Now wait.
生活是一种激情 对不对?
Life is passion. Isn't that true?
什么比女人还要更有激情呢?
What is more passionate than a woman?
要是一个女人决定了她的目标
If a woman can be what she decides to be,
要是一个女人可以遵从她内心的召唤
if a woman can love and follow her own calling,
那她就可以把握她自己的人生
then she can determine her own life.
我提议 为女人的激情干杯
I ask you to drink to woman's passion.
谁和我一起?
Who will drink with me?
我从来不会和任何人这样说话
I've never talked this way with anyone before.
我觉得我有点喝醉了
I feel as though I'm a bit drunk.
我猜我有点儿醉了!
Well, I AM a bit drunk, I suppose!
我从来没有见过像您这样的人 克莱曼斯
Never met anyone like you, Clemence.
不久 世上像我这样的女人会越来越多
The world will soon be filled with women like me.
你怎么选择呢 德妮丝?
But what about you, Denise?
除了售货员和妻子 你能做到更多的事情
There is too much about you to be a shop girl or a wife.
你想做什么呢?
What do you want to be?
是什么呢?
Qui est-il?
我...
I...
我想成为莫里
I want to be Moray.
我是说... 我不是想成为一个男人
I mean...I don't want to be a man.
我梦想能经营天堂百货
I dream of running The Paradise.
并不只是因为商店本身的魅力
Not just for the glamour of it,
尽管我很喜欢听到摩挲那些华美礼服时发出的声音
although I do like the idea of swishing around in a fine dress.
我是说工作本身 我喜欢这份工作
For the work. That is what I love.
当我有个想法 或者做出决定的时候
When I have an idea or make a decision
或者我有机会带头做些事情的时候 我感到...
or someone gives me the opportunity to take the lead, I feel...
我很难描述那种感觉
I can't quite describe it.
我会做很多事情 如果有机会...
There are so many things I would do if...
当我们直面我们的激情时 我们就自由了
When we admit to our passion, we are free.
我们就能得到想要的 成为我们想成为的人
We can have what we want, be who we want to be.
我就知道 你和我的想法一样
I knew you'd see things the same as I do.
对吗?
Is it true?
是的
It is true.
你真漂亮
You're so beautiful.
不行
No.
没有人会知道的 我们想做什么就做什么
No-one will know. We can have whatever we want.
可我知道啊
I'LL know.
这不是我想要的
I don't want this.
您可以听听我的建议 先生
Perhaps I could suggest, sir,
我们根据她的大概定价做出决定
we make a decision based on the prices she has outlined
- 就能确保正常供应了 - 不 我们先不提
- and the guarantee of a regular supply. - No. We wait.
要是她回巴黎了 没有在餐桌上和您定下协定呢?
What if she returns to Paris and there's been no dinner engagement?
哦 她会和我共进晚餐的
Oh, she will dine with me.
威斯顿先生 我了解克莱曼斯 她很轻浮
Mr Weston, I know Clemence. She is flighty.
当男人关心她的时候 她会挑逗戏耍他们
Where men are concerned, she likes to tease and play.
我了解克莱曼斯这样的女人 她们就是该被驯服的
I know women like Clemence. What they respond to is being mastered.
为什么因为她是个女人就要特殊考虑?
Why does it matter that she is a woman?
我们必须要考虑的是这宗交易
We must consider this business.
我们应该像对待其他供应商一样对她
We treat her as we do any other supplier.
我们都是男人 你懂我的意思
We are all gentlemen together. You know what I intend.
她令人难以抗拒 我为什么要抗拒?
I find her irresistible. Why should I resist?
威斯顿先生 克莱曼斯她可不会...
Mr Weston, Clemence does not...
对追求者有什么回应
respond to gentlemen suitors.
你是说她是一个贞洁的法国淑女?
You're telling me she's a chaste French maid?!
她更喜欢扮演一个诱惑者
She prefers the role of seducer.
你认为我没有办法破解她的防备?
You think I can't overcome her resistance?
我希望您别去尝试
I would prefer you did not try.
你试过了 是不是? 在巴黎的时候
You tried, didn't you? In Paris.
然后她拒绝了你
And she rejected you.
"我们都是男人"
"We're all gentlemen together."
我觉得我被迫加入了一个俱乐部
I feel I've been pressed into a club I have no wish to join.
要是他认为没必要在我们面前掩饰他的意图...
If he sees no reason to hide his intentions from us...
你是个专家 我是指 你在一群法国人中间生活过
You're the expert. I mean, you've lived amongst the French.
- 我们怎么处理这事儿? - 我们不插手
- How do we deal with this? - We don't.
她会处理好的
She does.
要是你...玩弄他的话 他就会和你对着干
If you...toy with him, he will set himself against you
我可不能保证你签下合同
and I cannot guarantee you will get the contract.
好吧 那你要我怎么做 亲爱的? 向他妥协?
Well, what would you have me do, darling? Submit to him?
躲起来? 逃走?
Hide away? Run away?
我提醒你 克莱曼斯
I warn you, Clemence,
汤姆・威斯顿是个复杂的男人
Tom Weston is made of a different mettle.
我不认为他可以欺凌我
I see no reason to let him bully me
因为他就是一个专横的被惯坏了的英国男人
because he's a spoiled Englishman used to having his own way.
你怎么想 德妮丝?
Do you, Denise?
- 您是否需要我回避一下 莫里先生 - 不用
- Do you want me to leave so you can talk, Mr Moray? - No.
不 不需要的 德妮丝
No, there's no need for that, Denise.
你是否想和他打交道?
Do you intend to take him on?
我喜欢像汤姆・威斯顿这样的男人
Well, I like men like Tom Weston
就是因为他们太好懂了
because it is so easy to know them.
这样的男人 要驯服他们易如反掌
Such men, it's a child's play to tame them.
呃 德妮丝 能否给我张纸?
Er, Denise, might I borrow some paper?
我会写张条儿给汤姆・威斯顿
I'm going to write to Mr Tom Weston
就告诉他我没有办法和他共进晚餐了
to tell him I cannot meet him for a dinner tonight.
女士 真是对不起 我拿错鞋子了
Ma'am, I'm so sorry, I've got the wrong pair.
我去给您取另外一双过来
I'll fetch the correct ones for you.
克莱拉 克莱曼斯小姐吻了我
Clara, Mademoiselle Clemence kissed me.
她吻你了?
She kissed you?
她想要引诱我
She wanted to seduce me.
但她是莫里的朋友 你有没有告诉他?
But she's Moray's friend. Have you told him?
- 我本该说的 - 那为什么不说?
- I should. - Then why don't you?
我不知道
I don't know.
如果她是个男人 你就会告诉他 对吧?
If she was a man you'd tell him, wouldn't you?
我希望她签下合同 我很烦恼
I want her to have the contract. I'm confused.
她说的那些 关于女人内心的欲求
Everything she said, about women having a calling
我们不应该这样带着...
and the wrongs that we live with...
姑娘们!
Girls!
姑娘们 我还没离职呢
Girls, I am not quite deposed yet.
我希望你们还能对我有点尊重
I hope you will show me the respect of my position
请保持到我从商店离开
until such a time as I am escorted from the premises.
克莱拉 现在没有人服侍巴顿女士
Clara, Mrs Barton is without attendance.
还有三周 那时我们可以...
It's only three Sundays, and then we can...
没必要去管那个木屋的情况
It doesn't matter what condition the cottage is in,
只要能够保暖就行
so long as we're warm.
莫里先生将要安排面试
Mr Moray is to conduct interviews.
为了我的职位
For my position.
那很重要
Well, that's grand.
给年轻女孩一些机会展示自己的能力
Give the younger girls a chance to stake a claim.
我们的德妮丝会很期望这事的
Our Denise'll be keen, I expect.
我没那么老
I am not so old.
还不是很老
Not so very old.
你自己说的 奥德丽 "在我们这个年龄"
You said it yourself, Audrey - "At our age".
我那时指的是烟火
I was referring to the firecrackers.
我没去工作还不到一天
There has not been one day when I have been absent from my work.
是的 不到一天你就失去话语权了
Yes, there has. That time you lost your voice.
我说的不是指几个男人
What I meant was no more than any man.
我们被男人统治了
We are ruled by men.
我们将会住在你哥哥的小屋 这是你的决定
We are going to live in your brother's cottage. Your decision.
为了跟你结婚我等了好多年 是你的决定
I've waited years to marry you. Your decision.
现在我们要急急忙忙地结婚了 也是你的决定
Now we are to marry in haste. Your decision.
如果女人就是这样被男人统治的 那我就太差劲了
If that is a woman ruled by men, then I'm a pincushion.
这些都是小事 我讲的是根本
Those are trifles. I am talking about fundamentals,
一个女人内心的呼唤
a woman's calling.
对我而言这不是小事 奥德丽
They are not trifles to me, Audrey.
如果你要求的话我会立即卖掉我的商店
I put my shop up for sale on your say-so.
你这么说是要改变主意了吗?
Are you telling me you want to change your mind?
我认为克莱曼斯小姐...
I think Mademoiselle Clemence...
并不关心男人
..does not care for men.
一点也不关心 她更喜欢折磨我们
Far from it. She likes nothing better than to bait us.
我的意思是...
What I meant was...
我认为她更喜欢女人
..I think she prefers women.
你为什么不告诉我?
Why didn't you tell me?
什么?
What?
你认为我会因为你嫉妒她就告诉你吗?
You think I should have told you because you were jealous of her?
好让你放松一下吗?
To put you at your ease?
讲她的私事不是我应该做的 德妮丝
It is not my place to tell her private business, Denise.
还没有买家吗 洛维特先生?
No buyers yet, Mr Lovett?
我不知道我还要不要卖这个店 山姆
I don't even know if I'm still selling up, Sam.
为什么? 发生什么事了?
Why? What's happened?
奥德丽似乎突然间认为
Audrey seems to suddenly believe that to marry
结婚是对女性的背叛
would be a betrayal of her sex.
那一定是小姐搞的鬼 我听到了她们在酒吧的谈话
That'll be Mademoiselle's doing. I heard 'em all talking in the inn.
- 奥德丽去过"三皇冠"? 不可能 - 是的
- Audrey in the Three Crowns? No. - Yes.
我都没去过那里
I don't even go in there.
- 那真像个聚会 - 我还在这里吃不好睡不好
- Oh, it was quite the party. - And here's me without a breath of sleep
担心我是不是还能结婚?
fretting about whether my marriage is on or off?
我对女人的认识就是 你要承诺你会永远爱她们
What I know about women is this - you promise them undying love,
婚姻与忠诚
marriage, faithfulness,
两者是不可分割的
they're away in a wisp.
如果你不在乎 就去那里看看吧
If you don't give a hoot, act the lad about town,
在那里你就是王子
chase you around like a prince.
好吧 我们今晚去旅馆 山姆
Right. We're going to the inn tonight, Sam.
- 我身无分文 - 我买单 把那些东西拿进来
- Haven't got a penny in my pocket. - I'm buying. Bring that lot in.
我们必须把最小的烟火放在前面
We must put the smallest firecrackers in the front,
一次只卖一个 那样人们才买得起
sell them one at a time so people can afford them.
我必须提醒你 小姐 合约毫无疑问是确定的
I must remind you, Mademoiselle, the contract is by no means certain.
但是我无条件相信莫里
Oh, but I have every faith in Moray.
那两蠢货还在装模作样
The two bulls are butting heads.
为什么男人认为装腔作势能吸引女人呢?
Why do men suppose that posturing is what catches a woman's eye?
吸引人的男人总是缄默的 像你这样的
The handsomest man is always the most reserved. Like you.
你说这话真是太奉承了 小姐
This is very flattering of you, Mademoiselle.
那不是奉承 别侮辱我 那是事实
It is not flattery. On m'a offense. It is the truth.
你最可爱的地方
The loveliest thing about you
就是你不知道你有多么美好
is that you have no idea of how beautiful you are.
原谅我吧 罗马尼斯小姐
Forgive me, Mademoiselle Romanis,
我不习惯女人这么开放 这么恭维
but I'm not used to women being quite so forward, so complimenting.
如果你请我共进晚餐 我不会拒绝的
If you were to ask me to a dinner, I would not refuse.
我是个有妇之夫
I am a married man.
我知道
I know that.
我认为与这样一个有魅力的女人共进晚餐是...
I would consider it improper to have dinner with such a...
不合适的
..an attractive woman.
没人会知道的
No-one would know.
你是在取笑我吗?
Are you making fun of me?
你没看到我看你的眼神吗?
Have you not seen the way I look at you?
我深深的被你吸引了
I am deeply attracted to you.
- 我决不能 - 我也看到了你看我的眼神
- I could never... - I also see the way you look at me.
是不确定吗?
Is it not true?
你是个非常美丽的女人
You are a very beautiful woman.
今晚当你躺下的时候 我会醒着
When your head lies on your pillow tonight, I'll be lying awake,
幻想你跟我在一起
wishing you were with me.
乔纳斯!
Jonas!
我应该知道 他是个男人 我应该警告他
I should've known - he's a man. I should've warned him
提醒他起床什么的 那样也许他就会躺在床上了
to get up and about, and then he might've stayed in bed.
你在外面做什么 乔纳斯?
What were you doing out there, Jonas?
我不记得啦
I don't remember.
我不记得我什么时候起床
I don't recall getting from my bed.
情况不妙 是吗?
That's not good, is it?
很糟糕 我想说
That's bad, I'd say.
达德利 你在这儿工作多久了?
Dudley. How long have you worked here?
莫里和我很小就来了 那时这里属于埃默森先生
Moray and I came here as boys, when Mr Emmerson owned the place.
那时还是小规模的交易
It was a great deal smaller then.
很感人... 想到两个穷小子
It is...touching, to think that two poor boys
成长到现在的地位
have risen to such status.
帅气的西装 丝质的领带...
Fine suits, silk ties...
你一定不会想到会有这么大的区别吧
You must not let such distinction go to your head.
我自己一直很感激我能有这些责任
I've always considered myself grateful for the responsibilities.
那你就别再跟罗马尼斯小姐纠缠不清了
Then you will have no more to do with Mademoiselle Romanis.
先生 我向你保证...
Sir, I assure you...
别否认我亲眼看到的事实
Do not contradict what my eyes have witnessed.
威斯顿先生 克莱曼斯告诉我的就是...
Mr Weston, sir, what I know of Clemence tells me...
我允许你说话了吗 莫里?
Did I ask for your intervention, Moray?
似乎每一天我都必须向你说明
It seems that with each passing day I must continue to convey
世界已经改变了
to you that the world has changed.
天堂百货不再属于你了
The Paradise is no longer your domain.
这里的生意将由我管理
Business here will be conducted at my bidding.
如果你想保留你在这里的位置 达德利
If you wish to retain your position here, Dudley,
你就别管克莱曼斯了 你明白吗?
you will leave Clemence be. Do you understand?
- 是的 先生 - 那就没什么事了
- Yes, sir. - Then all is well with the world.
我已经尽我所能容忍你的丈夫了
I have done my best to tolerate your husband
但是他威胁要解雇达德利
but he has threatened to dismiss Dudley.
我不会允许他那么做的
I will not allow him to do this.
你为什么把我叫到这里呢?
Why have you called me back here?
是为了恢复天堂百货吗? 那是不可能的
Is it to restore The Paradise? Because that is impossible
因为我一定要对付这种报复性的干涉
if I must contend with this kind of vindictive interference.
为什么汤姆想要除掉达德利呢?
Why would Tom wish to remove Dudley?
他似乎把达德利看成是竞争对手
He seems to consider Dudley as some kind of rival.
罗马尼斯小姐吗?
Ahh, Mademoiselle Romanis?
那就是你来这里的原因吗? 来刺激我?
Is that why you are here? To goad me?
我来这里是因为我觉得我必须来 凯瑟琳...
I-I came here because I felt I had to. Katherine...
我不需要你的可怜 我不会跟我丈夫分开的
I do not want your pity. I will make my own accommodation with my husband.
汤姆并不是他表现出来的那样
Tom is not what he appears to be to some people.
他是一个好丈夫 好父亲 军人都有一点...
He is a fine husband, and father. Military men are somet...
我来处理这事 谢谢 凯瑟琳 如果有需要我的
I will deal with this. Well, thank you, Katherine. If I can help...
你什么时候任命一个新的女装部主管?
When will you appoint a new Head of Ladieswear?
- 我们将进行面试 - 德妮丝是个绝佳的人选
- We will conduct interviews. - Denise will make an excellent appointment.
很显然她是最好的候选人
She is clearly the best candidate.
我们还要考虑其他的女孩
There...there are other girls we must consider.
克莱拉也很有能力...
Clara has qualities which...
你为什么不愿意选德妮丝呢?
Why would you hold Denise back?
有点说不过去
It makes no sense.
你考虑过其他人会怎么想吗?
Are you concerned what others will think
如果你支持你的情人?
if you favour your lover?
支不支持德妮丝跟你又有什么关系呢?
Why would it matter to you to champion Denise?
或许我应该感谢公平的价值
Perhaps I have come to appreciate the value of justice.
克莱曼斯小姐 我必须恳求你
Mademoiselle Clemence, I must plead with you
不要利用达德利先生
not to use Mr Dudley.
你不理解 德妮丝 我没得选择
You don't understand, Denise. I have no choice.
我离开巴黎是因为有一些... 困难
I left Paris because there was...some difficulty.
我不得不在这儿谋生 我必须把合同搞到手
I have to make a life here. I must have the contract.
- 不管怎样 你一定要用这种手段吗 - 是的
- Look, whatever the reasons, must you use such methods? - Yes, I must.
因为我是一个女人
Because I'm a woman.
如果我是男人汤姆・威斯顿会这样对我吗?
Would Tom Weston treat me in this way if I were a man?
他会让我一起讨论生意吗?
Will he offer me the engagement on purely business terms?
他不会让我这么得意 除非我满足他条件
He will prevent me from prospering unless I indulge him.
难道不是吗?
Is it not true?
那么我还没有权利动用一切必要手段
Then am I not entitled to use whatever means necessary
来获取平等吗?
to gain equality?
-
你不会这么做吗? - 不会
- Would you not do the same? - No.
那你就落后了
Then you will be left behind.
我来问你
Let me ask you this:
男人给你的一切
whatever has been given to you by men,
你不担心他们会再次从你身边带走吗?
do you not live in fear that they will take it away again?
我一直观察你 也从莫里那里知道你很有才华
I have watched you. I have heard Moray talk about your many gifts.
奥德丽女士离开后 你会接任她的职位吗?
When Miss Audrey leaves, will you be given her position?
我不知道
I don't know.
- 我... - 你想得到这个职位吗?
- I... - Do you want it?
你会争取吗?
Can you do it?
还有其他姑娘想...
There are other girls who just...
这个问题你一定要对自己坦诚 而不是对我
I give you the question you must answer to yourself. Not to me.
如果职位没有给你
If the position is not given to you,
你会关注心爱的男人
do you care more for the man you love
胜过关注自己的心声吗?
than you do for your own voice?
你是想当一个好姑娘? 默默地接受?
Will you be a good girl? Will you meekly accept?
还是会大声地说出自己的心声?
Or will you speak out?
噢!
Oh!
罗马尼斯小姐 谢谢你的光临
Mademoiselle Romanis, thank you for coming.
这边请
Please, this way.
乔纳斯? 嗯...
Jonas? Mmm...
乔纳斯?
Jonas?
亚瑟告诉我们了 他是怎样在桥边找到你的
Arthur told us how he found you at the bridge.
如果你在耍花招 我们不会上当的
If this was a trick, we are not falling for it.
这儿的人不会同情你
There is no sympathy for you here.
乔纳斯 过去的一年你是怎么过的?
What have you been up to this past year, Jonas?
流...流
Tr-tr...
呃 边流浪边工作
Er, tr-travels and...work.
你在向我们隐瞒什么?
What are you hiding from us?
你离开天堂百货后在做什么?
What have you been up to since you left The Paradise?
一直流浪 那就是我现在的生活
I have been on the road. That is my life now.
我不想再提这些心酸往事了 莫里先生
I would wish not to describe the hardship, in case
以免你因此自责
you should feel in...in some way responsible, Mr Moray.
莫里先生不会因你的遭遇而受任何谴责
Mr Moray is not to blame for your plight.
我们都要对自己的人生负责 我明天就会离开
We are all responsible for our own life. I shall be gone by tomorrow.
你到这来不是偶然 是吗?
It was not chance brought you here, was it?
不要认为你能收买我们  我警告你...
If you believe you can bribe us, I warn you...
达德利!
Dudley!
我们很欢迎你一直住在这 直到你身体完全康复
You are welcome to remain here until you are fully recovered.
感激不尽 先生
I am most grateful, sir.
你真无情 我从没见过你这么愤怒
You were so merciless. I've never seen you so riled.
一见到他我就生气
That man has got beneath my skin.
他生病了 我们就不能...
He's ill. Can we not just...
- 不是乔纳斯 是汤姆・威斯顿 - 我保证
- Not Jonas. Tom Weston. - I promise you,
没什么可担心的 我会处理好汤姆的事
there is nothing for you to worry about. I will deal with Tom,
但有一件事他似乎说得不对
and it's not as though he's right.
你不是那种会追求克莱曼斯的人
You're not the kind of man to go chasing after Clemence.
当然不是
No.
我结婚比较早 生命里只有一个女人
I married young. I've only ever known one woman's kiss.
所有人都知道我是什么样的人
Everyone knows what kind of man I am.
噢 亲爱的 原来你在这
Oh, darling. There you are.
我邀请了克莱曼斯小姐这段时间来我们家住
I have invited Mademoiselle Clemence to stay with us during her time here.
我可看不下去她再住在闷热的小旅馆里了
I can't bear the thought of her in that stuffy hotel,
我知道你们两个也想一起谈生意
and I know you two wish to talk business.
这样合作不是会更愉快吗?
It will be so much more convivial, don't you think?
是的
I do.
我告诉艾德蒙我想要重新考虑一下
I have told Edmund that I may want reconsider.
所以我叔叔才放下了"商店出售"的牌子
So that's why my uncle's taken down the "For Sale" sign.
奥德丽女士 你不是说怀疑和推迟
Miss Audrey, did you not say it was the doubt and delay
让你很不开心吗?
that was making you so unhappy?
为什么女人因为结婚要受惩罚?
Why should a woman be punished for marrying?
残忍的法国女人! 看她对我们做了什么
That bloody French woman! Look at what she's doing to us.
她来了 厄运也来了
She comes here, all hell is let loose,
然后她走了 留给我们一堆烂摊子
and then she'll be gone and leave us with the consequences.
我以为你们年轻姑娘能明白她是在为我们抱不平
I thought you younger women would see that she speaks for us all.
奥德丽女士 这儿没人认为
Miss Audrey, no-one here believes
迫使一个女人离开是对的
it's right for a woman to be pressed
但你答应艾德蒙叔叔后又反悔就对了吗?
into leaving, but to do this to Uncle Edmund after you promised him?
这和你人生中其他的选择一样
You have the same choice now you've had all your life.
是什么让你改变了主意? 挑战男人?
What's made you change your mind? Is it to defy men?
- 还是争取自身的幸福? - 我明白了
- Or is it to strive for your own happiness? - I see.
老母鸡快要离巢了
When the old hen's about to leave the perch,
小鸡崽们开始梳理自己的羽毛了
the young hens certainly do start to flutter their feathers.
和克莱曼斯小姐相处
It is such a pleasant diversion,
真是愉快极了
having Mademoiselle Clemence to stay with us.
她性格大胆直率
She is quite the firecracker.
我明白男人们为什么对她如此着迷了
I can see why men fall for her.
也知道为什么你会痴迷于她了 亲爱的
I can see why you might fall for her, my darling.
他告诉你的吗?
Did he tell you?
莫里来找你了?
Did Moray come to see you?
如果你要追求她 就在这儿吧
If you are going to pursue her, then you will do it here,
绝对安全 不要在公众场合 也不要在天堂百货
out of harm's way. Not so publicly. NOT at The Paradise.
还有 请不要让弗罗拉看到你讨好她
And please, do not let Flora see you fawning after her.
你看到我讨好过别的女人吗?
Have you ever known me to fawn after anyone?
哦 我第一次见到你的时候你就谄媚极了
Oh, when we first met you were quite the flatterer.
为什么你这么在意天堂百货?
Why are you so sensitive about The Paradise?
我希望我们不要给莫里提供任何帮助
I want us to do nothing to give Moray the upper hand.
你可以用任何手段打击他 但不要摧毁他
You can jostle with him, by all means, but do not crush him.
让他在那儿有安全感
I want him to feel safe there.
我绝不相信是你抛弃了他
I never believed that you abandoned him.
如果不是他伤了你的心 为什么你要毁灭他?
Why would you need to destroy him, if he hadn't broken your heart?
我带克莱曼斯小姐回家...
I brought Mademoiselle Clemence into our home...
..是因为我知道我阻止不了你
..because I have learned I cannot stop you.
你也阻止不了自己
Because you cannot stop yourself.
我还知道这一切都将变成过眼云烟 她也是
And I have learned that it will pass, she will pass.
当激情退去
And when the passion passes...
你内心充满愧疚...
..and you are overcome with shame...
..我会接你回家 安慰你
..I will pick you up and comfort you.
好好爱你 做你的好妻子
I will love you and be a good wife to you.
但我的爱是有条件的  汤姆
But I do not love you freely, Tom.
作为交换 你不准再过问
In exchange, you will not ask me again about what happened
我和莫里之间的瓜葛
between Moray and I.
什么事让你这么晚偷偷跑到我这来了?
What brings you creeping up here at night?
我现在进退两难
I have a dilemma.
我不知道怎么办
I don't know what to do.
- 你想征求我的意见? - 是的
- You would ask my guidance? - Of course.
我知道即使很难回答你也会告诉我答案
I know that you'll tell me the truth, even if it is difficult.
而且直觉告诉我你知道我该怎么做
And something told me you'd know what I should do.
关于小姐的?
The Mademoiselle?
她好像故意引诱达德利先生
She seems intent on seducing Mr Dudley.
你还没有告诉达德利先生
And you haven't told Mr Dudley
你知道她对他有什么企图吗?
what you know about her motives towards him?
如果我告诉达德利了先生 这...
If I speak to Mr Dudley about it, it...
就好像我在谴责他
..it would be as though I'm accusing him
意图对妻子不忠
of wanting to be unfaithful to his wife,
我不知道我能否办得到
and I don't know that I can do that.
达德利先生到这来了 我从没听过他那样讲话
Mr Dudley came here, talking as I've never heard him talk before.
他很愤怒 内心很挣扎
He was like a man on fire. A man at war with himself.
他的口袋里有一张洒了香水的卡片 可能是邀请函
He had a scented card in his pocket. An invitation, probably.
我怀疑今晚他会去见她
I suspect he will meet with her tonight.
艾德蒙?
Edmund?
亲爱的 我可以私下和你说几句话吗?
Might we speak privately, my dear?
我献身给这家酒吧了
I'm rather wedded to the bar.
有什么话就在这说吧
You can say whatever you want to say right here.
你似乎理解错了我的决定
You seem to have taken my decision rather personally.
你不能理解的是 我的推理中涉及到的
What you fail to appreciate is that my reasoning concerns
女性被迫放弃工作的不公平性
the injustice to a woman having to give up her position.
那我必须放弃的东西呢?
What about what I must give up?
我就没有努力让小商店存活下来
Have I not fought to keep my little shop alive
度过最艰难的时期吗?
through the worst of times?
你认为我举起"商店出售"的牌子
Do you suppose I put up a "For Sale" sign
就像系鞋带一样容易吗?
as easily as tying my shoelace?
这对我来说如切肤之痛
It is a wrench to my heart.
但是我心甘情愿
But I did it willingly.
我以为你也会如此
I thought you would do the same.
但是我错了 我现在明白了
I was wrong. I see that now.
老板再来一杯 我比这黑夜还沧桑啊!
Let us have ale, Landlord. The night is younger than I am!
给你表演一个 看到这枚硬币没?
Let me show you this. You see this coin?
好 我们把它放在这只手上 请说"嘛咪嘛咪轰"
OK, we're going to put it in this hand. Can you say, "abracadabra"?
- "嘛咪嘛咪轰"! - 然后吹口气
- Abracadabra! - And now blow.
啊 它不见了! 去哪了呢? 再吹口气
Oh, it's not there! Where is it? Blow now.
这儿也没有! 弗罗拉你对它做了什么?
Oh, it's not here too! What did you do with it, Flora?
- 我什么也没干 - 哦我看见它了!
- I didn't do anything. - Oh, I see it!
- 天啊 - 在你的头发里!
- Oh, mon Dieu! - It was in your hair!
- 我在你头发里发现的 给你了 - 谢谢
- And because I found it in your hair, it's for you. - Thank you.
这顿晚餐真是其乐无穷
It has been the most delightful dinner,
但是抱歉
but I hope you will forgive me.
我还有个约会
I have another engagement.
我知道这很无礼 但这就是法国人
It is rude of me, I know, but it is the way in France.
我们大半个晚上奔波于各个约会
We flit about half the night,
并且我是这儿最不安分的法国女人
and I'm the most restless Frenchwoman there is.
克莱曼斯你是我们的客人 你来去自由
You are our guest, Clemence. You must come and go as you wish.
你真纵容我 我爱死了被纵容的感觉
Oh, you are spoiling me, and I do so like being spoiled.
谢谢 再会 感谢
Merci. Au revoir. Merci.
- 你去哪儿? - 我有个约会
- Where are you going?  - I have arranged a rendezvous.
和男人?
With a man?
我想约谁就约谁
I can meet whoever I want to.
我从不擅长和女孩子交往哈
I was never much good at talking to girls. Huh.
我可以和她们一起共事
At work, I could pass the time with them,
但是约会什么的 我总是害羞又笨拙
but romance, ha! I was always too shy, too awkward.
选择店中最文静的女孩会让我比较自信
I chose the most quiet girl in the shop. It made me feel confident.
我不想背叛我的妻子
I don't want to betray my wife.
你真是个英俊的男人
You are a beautiful man.
威斯顿先生
Mr Weston, sir.
我是乔纳斯 乔纳斯・弗兰克斯
I am Jonas. Jonas Franks.
罗马尼斯小姐在吗?
Is Mademoiselle Romanis here?
这个点了她怎么会在这呢 先生?
Why would she be here at this time of night, sir?
我觉得她和某个男人有牵扯
I believe she has a liaison with a man.
先生 请容我说两句
Sir, if I may,
我观察过这位法国女士这段时间
I have observed the French lady in her time here,
在这儿与女士们先生们的交往
both with gentlemen and with her own sex.
你要是问我她今晚去哪儿了 不可能是和一个男人
If you were to ask me where she was tonight, it would not be with a man.
肯定是和男人
It cannot be.
先生 我不要求您认同我
You need not accept my consideration, sir,
虽然我要了解人们的处事方式和弱点
though I have taught myself well to know people,
是手到擒来的
their ways...and their weaknesses.
在这个问题上我建议您去咨询莫里先生
Might I suggest you consult with Mr Moray on this matter?
莫里...了解这个?
Moray...knows?
他没告诉我 但是我能分辨出来
He has not told me so himself, but I can tell.
请允许我推荐他
May I suggest you ask him?
克莱曼斯小姐! 你在这干什么?
Mademoiselle Clemence! What are you doing here?
那个男人! 乔纳斯!
That man! Jonas!
我从来没有这么怕过握手
I was never so afraid of the touch of a hand.
我感觉我...我不敢拒绝他
I felt I...I do not dare to refuse him.
- 达德利先生在哪? - 我不知道
- Where is Mr Dudley?  - I don't know.
他把达德利 带走了
He took Dudley away.
他看我的眼神 他对我说的话...
That way he looked at me, the things he said to me...
好像他之前认识我一样
It was like he knew me.
乔纳斯先生想了解你就能对你了如指掌
Mr Jonas will know all there is to know about you.
小姐 你对达德利先生兴趣不大
Mademoiselle, you've shown such little regard for Mr Dudley.
你为什么非得让他颜面扫地?
Why are you so determined to make him face his own weaknesses?
我们能与你感同身受
Your tale will be the same as the rest of us.
人...是脆弱的
Human...weak.
当我和你一般年纪时 我曾爱过一个人
I did love someone once. I was young, as young as you are now.
我见到那个姐姐时 我就知道她是我的真命天女
I met an older woman and I knew she was what I'd been waiting for.
我放纵自己爱上了她 我很无助
I let myself love her. I was helpless.
我肯定她会离开她丈夫 和我在一起
I felt sure she would leave her husband to be with me.
慢慢地 我察觉她没这想法
Slowly, I learned she had no such intentions.
她要生活在正轨上
She wanted what was considered proper.
她为爱上我而自我厌恶 我从来没那样过
She hated herself for loving me. I would never do that.
我决不因自己的性向自我惩罚
I would never punish myself for the way that I love.
她嫁的是一个像达德利先生那样的人?
She was married to a man like Mr Dudley?
一个忠诚稳重的男人
A good and faithful man.
居家好男人
A family man.
她怎么可以选他不选我?
How could she choose him over me?
我给她这激情四射的生活 她为什么不要?
How could she choose that life when I offered her such passion?
来了 来了!
I'm coming, I'm coming!
大家来这儿 三更半夜比上班时间
More people come to this door in the dead of night
跑得还勤!
than during business hours!
什么女人忍心折磨这样可爱的灵魂呐?
What kind of a woman would torment such a dear soul?
拒绝和爱的人结婚
What kind of a fool would refuse an offer of marriage
她得多蠢?
from the man she loves?
我不知道你拒绝了
I didn't know you had refused.
- 我没拒绝 - 而且我并没有求婚
- I didn't. - And there wasn't an offer.
- 你提议的 - 确实
- You asked me. - I did.
好吧...我现在求婚
Well...I'm asking you now.
你回答是的时候 不能有任何迟疑
And if you say yes, there's to be no untying or doubting
- 勉强或是犹豫... - 知道了
- or declining or hesitating... -  I will.
- 乔纳斯? - 马车在等你
- Jonas? - There's a carriage waiting to take you home, sir.
你必须在员工到来前离开
You must leave before the staff arrive.
他们不能看到你这个样子
They must not see you like this.
我怎么会在这儿?
What am I doing here?
先生 已经给您的妻子送去便条 告知你逗留
A note was sent to your wife, sir, to say that you were detained
在莫里先生这 请她不必忧心
overnight by Mr Moray, and there was nothing for her to worry about.
是克莱曼斯...
Clemence...
什么也没发生 先生
Nothing happened, sir.
你没惹上麻烦
There is nothing for you to be troubled by.
先生 马车在等 我们得抓紧了
The carriage, sir. We must make haste.
克莱曼斯在街上安排了一个烟花宴
Clemence has arranged a demonstration of her firecrackers,
不管有没有我们 她决定这么做了
on the street. She has decided to go ahead, with or without us.
会吸引大批的人
It will draw quite a crowd.
他们肯定想知道去哪买这烟花
They will want to know where they can buy the fireworks.
最终 这纯粹是商业问题
In the end, this is purely a business matter.
让她签合同 摆脱她我们干
Give her the contract, let's be rid of her.
我们会努力达到
We'll all strive to maintain
- 您的标准 奥德丽小姐 - 荒谬
- the standards you have set us, Miss Audrey. - Nonsense.
我走到街尾前就能忘个一干二净
I will be forgotten before I reach the end of the street.
由你来...我有点怀疑
I have little doubt it will be you...
你知道吗 克莱曼斯小姐说得对
Mademoiselle Clemence is correct in what she says, you know.
保重 德妮丝 别慌 我们不会跑了的
Take care. Don't fuss, our Denise. We're not vanishing entirely.
商店都还没卖出去
Haven't even sold the shop yet.
奥德丽 我们这把年纪了 快乐稍纵即逝
At our age, Audrey, you have to take the happiness
理应乐在当下
when it comes after you.
别管它是不是庸俗的
Even if it is tasteless and vulgar.
驾
Walk on.
乔纳斯
Jonas.
达德利告诉我了你为他做的事
Dudley told me what you did for him.
先生 你得提防威斯顿先生 我懂他那样的人
You must be careful of Mr Weston, sir. I have known men like him.
他会和敌人同归于尽
He would destroy himself in order to destroy his enemies.
乔纳斯你要去哪?
Where are you going, Jonas?
南方 达德利先生 天气暖点
South, Mr Dudley. I seek a warmer climate.
要是我们请你留下呢?
What if we were to ask you to stay?
为什么你没告诉莫里?
Why didn't you tell Moray?
- 我不知道 - 你懂的 德妮丝
- I don't know. - You do know, Denise.
你说的许多话都是对的
Because so many of the things you said are true,
我想要谨记
and I want to keep them.
再见
Goodbye.
我们一周都在申请...
We have, all week been taking applications...
接手奥德丽小姐空出的职位
for the post vacated by Miss Audrey.
失败? 失误?
Failure? Mistakes?
你到底信不信我有能力接替奥德丽的位置?
Do you even believe me capable of filling Miss Audrey's shoes?
实话说 我不能忍受选择的又是你不是我
Truth is, I cannot bear to have you chosen over me, again.
如果你选择和我交锋 我会让你想起来
If you choose to cross swords with me, I will make you remember
你嫁的是个士兵 我会给你迎面痛击!
you married a soldier. I will meet you head-on!
你是他们游戏中双方的棋子 你的处境并不安全
You're both pawns in their game, that is not a safe thing to be.
德妮丝 有人想和你私下谈谈
Denise, there is someone who would like a word with you privately.
洛维特小姐
Miss Lovett.